Go secure the crystal!
Hmm.
At this rate. we won't get there in time.
This way!
What do we do?
The crystal's installation is complete.
and the final calibrations
on the cannon are already underway.
Everyone aim
for the center of the kyber cannon.
Come on. there's no time to waste!
Don't let them anywhere near the fortress.
Annihilate them damn rocks!
I won't let you stop us!
There's too much counter-fire.
we can't get in closer.
Kara. Ethan. come in. what's your status?
Can you destroy the cannon?
Ethan. Ethan!
Can you hear me?
Yeah. yeah. I copy.
Bad news. We haven't even reached
the command center.
Keep at it.
We'll attack the turret regardless.
Kwana. focus your attack
on the power unit!
What? Wait. But if we do that...
If we make them crash
onto Hy Izlan.
it will disable the cannon
and buy us time. right?
That would work in theory.
but what about you?
You don't have to worry about us.
We'll figure something out!
Four-Nines. get us out of here.
Use autopilot
to remotely control the ships.
I'm sure
young Kara can handle herself.
All right. you rogues.
Our target has changed.
Blow the engines.
we're gonna take that whole
floating junk heap down.
- Roger that!
Yep. Roger.
We did what we could. Kara!
Kara!
The rest is up to you.
I thought you said
you were gonna figure something out?
I'm working on it.
Whoa.
The Force is so strong with her.
Damage to main engine.
Emergency landing on Hy Izlan.
Redirect power to the control thrusters.
Continuing descent.
All right. we may have survived.
but that wasn't
as much damage as we'd hoped.
Nawaam...
Any damage to the kyber cannon?
No functional damage detected.
Then we fire
as soon as preparations are complete.
And we use it
to take out their defensive fleet.
Our own forces
will be in the line of fire.
That's irrelevant.
Understood.
Preparing to fire.
Charging the kyber cannon.
Preparing to fire...
Look. Lord Dunbai. Lady Tafflah.
They're already
preparing to fire the cannon.
Get your ships as far away as possible.
That's not an option.
It's too destructive a weapon.
If they fire it. it will tear a hole
right through the galaxy.
And I do not plan on seeing
a repeat of what happened to Bibin.
We are going to settle the score.
no matter what it takes.
Hmm. All ships. descend on Hy Izlan!
It looks like it's still up to us.
after all.
Kyber crystal status.
Charging in progress.
Weapons set up.
Calibrate and align kyber cannon.
Roger.
Destroy every last one of them!
Huh?
Enemy forces
have just infiltrated the control room.
They are indeed tenacious.
As a mark of respect.
I think I shall
take care of them personally.
So you have chosen to return.
Master Zhima?
It would be irresponsible of me
to allow the weight of your crimes
to grow any greater.
What's wrong. Kara?
My father and Nawaam
are fighting each other right now.
Can you not see that your way
only allows power-hungry fools
and criminals to flourish.
while the average
good-natured individual suffers?
Those who resist deserve to suffer.
I have amassed enough power
to force every being to yield to me.
You're wrong.
You will never impose your will
on others by using strength alone.
Fine. Master.
I am no longer in need of you.
Nothing will stand in my way.
including you.
Is there nothing that will sway you?
Kara!
Uh. my father...
I never wanted to cross blades with you.
So then you've been holding back.
You underestimated me. didn't you?
Ah. yes. You used that saber
to cut down your master.
All right then.
show me what you're truly capable of.
- Someone's coming!
- Hmm?
Zhima?
Nawaam...
Let me guess.
You were expecting Zhima?
Father...
I will not allow you
to destroy the kyber cannon.
I'd sooner kill you all. like I did Zhima.
You'll pay for that.
Oh. your saber is also silver.
Interesting.
Leave him to me.
You go and secure the crystal.
Kara! No!
Ethan. we have to get to the cannon.
There's nothing we can do to help her.
She's on her own.
Our job right now
is to destroy that cannon.
You can now tame your emotions.
Too bad you still
will not be able to defeat me.
You're not bringing order to the galaxy
with any of the things you're doing.
You're conquering it.
And what's the difference?
If you use domination to rule.
then the people will rebel.
Leaders who control without compassion
are doomed to be overthrown.
That's nonsense.
It's sad.
You were just a child
all alone with no one to teach you.
Forced to make it on your own.
Are you trying to tell me you pity me?
That's not it.
You say you've been attempting
to make your heart empty.
But inside your heart was that little boy.
And that is not a state of nothingness.
How dare you?
It's already halfway charged.
How about the energy supply.
can't we just shut it off?
If we can't hack
into their system.
then we physically destroy the cannon.
How are we supposed
to break a piece of junk that size?
All right.
If we can't damage the cannon.
then we have to destroy the kyber crystal!
This is the great
and sacred crystal of Hy Izlan
that Juro himself swore to protect.
But we have no other choice.
When my father cut down his master.
it was because he had no other choice.
Afterwards. he gave up his blade.
so he wouldn't fall to the dark side.
If you insist
on ruling over others like this.
you will end up being consumed
by the dark side.
Your notions of light and dark
are nothing but antiquated nonsense.
Being bound by those distinctions
will never bring stability to the galaxy.
There's no damage.
No. wait!
Did you forget
we're in the middle of something?
Did you not see that just now?
Do you have any idea
how many innocent people will die
if you fire that cannon
even one more time?
This is what makes the Jedi weak.
Their limits.
You should not let something such
as empathy distract you from your goals.
no matter how many sacrifices are made.
That isn't true!
What just happened?
What did I just do?
I cut through him.
But. he's still alive.
You didn't want
to kill anyone anymore.
Isn't that right?
I see...
So by your calculations. that was
only a fraction of its full power?
Uh...
We've got to do something
about this... fast.
- What?
- It seems we can't even get close to it.
Hmm.
Wretched thing!
What is this I'm seeing?
How is this possible?
How is your saber green?
You would abandon the state of nothingness
for the path of the Jedi?
Don't you see?
The Jedi aren't capable
of even their own cause!
This saber is merely responding
to what is inside my heart.
You'll sacrifice countless lives
to achieve your vision.
And that is evil.
Good and evil are no different in the end.
They're two halves of the same whole.
Unless you accept both. you will be lost.
Uh...
Your blade is showing you
what the color of your heart is now.
Father...
Hmm.
How am I not dead?
No. wait. I am dead. after all.
She used the Force
to shut off the lightsaber's blade.
Impossible.
Kara has reached a point far
beyond what you and I have ever attained.
I was defeated.
Break!
Fire.
Uh...
The kyber cannon
has been destroyed.
The fortress engines have been destroyed.
Communications system
will be shut down shortly.
What happened. where's Nawaam?
Presumed eliminated by a Jedi.
Oh...
You did it. Kara.
You've come so far.
Father?
In the end. it turns out
his heart wasn't empty after all.
- Hey. Kara!
- Huh?